Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/johnccoffin (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Banking
Capital Markets
Commercial Banking

John Coffin

Founder & President at Practical Growth Advisors
Greater Atlanta Area

Summary

Financial Services and Sales executive with proven business leadership success and extensive experience serving privately held companies and entrepreneurs. Innovative leader and entrepreneur with a record of developing effective strategies, executing business initiatives and recruiting/motivating diverse origination teams.

Specialities:

Forecasting and developing growth roadmaps
Sales, execution and growth strategies
Data driven analysis to improve decision making
Debt and equity capital advisory
M&A due diligence and integration

Experience

Practical Growth Advisors Founder & President 2018 - Present (2 years) Atlanta, Georgia, United States

Practical Growth Advisors provides strategic advisory and forecasting services to privately held companies to enable them to grow faster with confidence. Through PGA's customized financial and operating forecast platform, we create a dynamic, data-driven roadmap for growth and accelerated value creation. PGA serves private companies up to \$250MM of revenue and provides forecasting, data analytics, software application development and capital advisory services.

Atlantic Capital Bank
Co-Founder and EVP, New Market Development, Capital Markets and
Financial Institutions Group
2016 - 2018 (2 years)
Atlanta, GA

(A \$2.8B of assets bank providing differentiated banking products and financing solutions to emerging growth and mid-market companies and private

banking clients. Initial private capital raise of \$125MM in 2007 was the largest denovo bank start-up in U.S. history. Atlantic Capital (publicly traded on NASDAQ: ACBI) has grown to over \$450MM of market capitalization).

Responsible for new market development for both acquisition opportunities and new market startups.

- Developed strategic market assessments of the business conditions,
 M&A targets and banker availability in seven Southeastern MSAs to determine acquisition and market startup opportunities.
- Developed acquisition dialogue with numerous bank targets.
- Opened Charlotte, NC office in June 2017 after recruiting five senior bankers.

Atlantic Capital Bank
Co-Founder and EVP, Head of Corporate and Private Banking
2006 - 2015 (9 years)

Atlanta, GA

Recruited the executive and banking team, co-authored the private placement memorandum, participated in the capital raise/regulatory approval process and operating platform buildout during the bank's organization period from August 2006 until the opening in May 2007. Bank opened with 35 employees. Led team of Atlanta Corporate and Private Bankers.

- Built high performing culture and a differentiated banking experience based on our team's expertise, customized financing solutions, efficient treasury services platform and excellent client services.
- Responsible for strategic and marketing direction, business development and client service efforts of the team, as well as incentive compensation plan design and implementation.
- Grew organically through economic downturn to over \$775MM of loan commitments, \$810MM of client deposits, and a client base of over 750 corporate and 500 private banking clients.
- Designed and executed sales framework across banking and credit functions, leading to 30%+ growth in key performance metrics.
- Architected and drove Salesforce CRM implementation across the bank.

Wells Fargo 10 years

SVP and Commercial Banking Team Leader, Wachovia Bank 2003 - 2006 (3 years)

Atlanta, GA

Led management and origination activities of half of the Atlanta commercial banking team.

- Provided transaction leadership and interacted with key clients to maximize deal opportunities.
- Built strong team dynamics following SouthTrust merger and successfully managed transition issues.
- Responsible for business development and client retention for over 1,000 targeted clients and prospects across metro Atlanta.

Managing Director/SVP - Corporate & Investment Banking, Wachovia Bank

1996 - 2003 (7 years)

Greater Atlanta Area

Led the Northeast and Southeast (excluding Georgia) Corporate Banking team (1998-2001) and the Business Services Corporate & Investment Banking team (2001-2003) following the First Union merger.

Chase

VP, Media and Telecommunications Group, Manufacturers Hanover Trust/Chemical Bank/Chase Manhatten

1988 - 1996 (8 years)

New York, NY

Managed client relationships, executed syndicated bank financings and marketed corporate finance products to multimedia, cable television, publishing, broadcasting and film/television production companies.

Responsible for developing client relationships, negotiating transaction terms/ structure, conducting due diligence and managing a portfolio of over \$1B in

Education

exposure.

Columbia Business School

MBA, Finance and International Business · (1993)

Dartmouth College

BA, English · (1988)

Phillips Exeter Academy

 \cdot (1984)